pakistanherald.com 2009-11-09

# Privacy Policy | Pakistan Herald

---  
  
|  **Privacy Policy**  
---  
  
Introduction 

**Pakistanherald.com** provides interactive environments on the Internet to enable members to express themselves and share their ideas and interests by creating and participating in discussion-based virtual communities. One of our goals at Pakistanherald.com is to respect the privacy rights of anyone who joins Pakistanherald.com or visits any of our communities. Except as set forth within this privacy statement and within the scope of our community and content guidelines, we do not release personally identifiable information about our individual members and visitors without their permission. Our view is that our members and visitors are the ones who should generally control whether or not they share any personal information and how that information is used if it is shared. Furthermore, we believe that it is our responsibility to provide something of value in exchange for any information shared — in our case, discussion forums, email, and other free services. We appreciate your interest in and support of Pakistanherald.com and pledge to you our continued commitment to make our services better and better while enabling you — our members and visitors — to be comfortable with respect to your online privacy. To contact Pakistanherald.com about technical problems, to report a violation of our guidelines, to inquire about advertising within our domain, or any other item of interest or concern, please send us an email sysadmin@pakistanherald.com.

Pakistanherald.com respects the privacy of all those who spend any amount of time in our communities. We do collect information from our members and visitors. This is a statement of the use of the information that we collect, and if or how any of it is disseminated. If you have questions regarding this Statement of Privacy or feel that Pakistanherald.com has violated it in any way, please contact us at privacy@pakistanherald.com, so that we may address this issue. 

What information do we compile and use? And what methods do we use to collect information? 

We give notice to everyone prior to collecting any personally identifiable information. Such personally identifiable information will be used only for the purposes stated at the time of collection, and within this Statement on Privacy. Pakistanherald.com does not share any personally identifiable information with outside parties for commercial purposes, unless stated at the time of collection. The option is given, at the time of collection, not to allow Pakistanherald.com to share such information with outside parties. If such an option is taken, we will not share such information with outside parties; however, we do reserve the right to release that information concerning a member when the member partakes in an illegal activity, or for a member who we believe is in violation of our content guidelines, even without a subpoena, warrant, or other court order. Pakistanherald.com hopes that all third parties involved adhere to our policies regarding the privacy of our members; however, Pakistanherald.com does not assume any responsibility for any actions of third parties. For everyone who visits the Pakistanherald.com domain, we log IP addresses, the type of operating system that the visitor's computer uses, and the type of browser software used by the visitor. From the IP address, we can determine the Internet Service Provider and the geographic location of the visitor's point of connectivity. If a visitor wants to simply use Pakistanherald.com in a generic way (i.e. reading, but no personalization and no posting), they are not required to register. However, if a visitor wants to take advantage of the personalized products and services offered at Pakistanherald.com (i.e.vote, give comments, write an article, automatic login, subscriptions, posting etc.), we require that the visitor become a registered member by providing us with their name, zip/postal code, username, password and valid email address. 

Currently, Pakistanherald.com is using cookies, and, as with all online companies who do, we are continually evaluating our use of this information. A "cookie" is a file transferred from a website to the hard drive of your computer so that the website may track your activities on the website. A cookie will not let a website know any personally identifying information about you, such as your real name, address, etc., unless you previously provided that information at the website or have set your preferences in your browser to provide that information. Pakistanherald.com is not generally interested in any one individual and does not collect personally identifiable information about any one person using cookies. Cookies are a way for us to track who has seen which ads, how often pages are visited, and what the most popular areas of Pakistanherald.com are, so that we can improve our site and services and can keep from showing you the same ad too many times. We do not monitor the use of e-mail accounts, unless prompted by a request from a legal authority or in instances in which the activities of the user are interfering in the daily operation of Pakistanherald.com. 

We do use the information provided in the registration process as we have set forth within this Statement on Privacy and within the scope of our community and content guidelines. In our discussion forums, we do save all posted messages. This discussion content is kept for an indeterminate amount of time and is accessible to all members and visitors at Pakistanherald.com. Pakistanherald.com may also choose to highlight some of the best discussions taking place on its website. 

We do not allow our members or visitors to use Pakistanherald.com for the purpose of gathering personally identifiable information for commercial or unlawful purposes. Pakistanherald.com does not, however, control the acts of its members and visitors. All members and visitors should be aware that, when they disclose personal information such as their actual name, member name, e-mail address, etc., the information may be collected and used by others to send that person unsolicited e-mail from other parties, outside Pakistanherald.com. Pakistanherald.com does provide a free web email service to help its members avoid such email abuse. In the event that you encounter any Pakistanherald.com member who is improperly collecting or using information about users, please contact admin@pakistanherald.com
